2degreesmobile.co.nz 2019-03-09

# Privacy Policy | 2degrees Mobile

Last updated: 17 July 2017 [](https://www.2degreesmobile.co.nz/termsofuse/privacy-policy/#print)

### Who’s who

In this Privacy Policy: 

“you” means you, our customer and/or user of the 2degrees services and website.

“we”, “our”, “us” and “2degrees” means Two Degrees Mobile Limited and/or Two Degrees New Zealand Limited and includes any of our related companies.

### Purpose

To deliver the highest standard of service, we will ask you to provide us with personal information from time to time.  At 2degrees, we believe it is important that you know how we treat that information.

This policy outlines how and why we collect information from you, how we store it, how you can access and correct that information and when we might disclose information to other people.

This privacy policy also confirms 2degrees’ obligations under the Privacy Act 1993 and the Telecommunications Information Privacy Code 2003. For more information about how your personal information is protected under the Privacy Act 1993 and the Telecommunications Information Privacy Code 2003 visit [www.privacy.org.nz](http://www.privacy.org.nz/).

### Collection

We will collect information about you when you visit our website and mobile application sites, complete 2degrees application forms, enter 2degrees promotions or competitions, sign up for Your 2degrees and/or Your 2degrees Broadband (for instance, your name, address, contact number(s), email address, etc), and when you call our Customer Care or when we make any calls to you.   

We will also collect information about you when you buy and use 2degrees products and services (such as call and text message information (including date, time, some content, duration, and the number contacted), and information on your browsing activity that occurs when you are using our internet services (such as websites you have visited, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, when an internet browsing session is started and ended using your account, and any content you may access using any online content service we provide). We may also look at where your mobile device is from time to time, and how much you’re spending.

Other entities, like marketing organisations and credit reference agencies, may also provide us with information about you from time to time.

If you choose not to provide information when we ask for it, certain services and/or product features may not work properly or we may not be able to provide you with service or a product altogether.

### Use

We hold and use the information we collect for a number of purposes, including:

  * Processing application forms and any online transactions you make;
  * Carrying out credit checking and scoring (if you have agreed);
  * Billing you;
  * Providing and assisting you with product(s) or service(s) you request;
  * Monitoring compliance with the terms and conditions of 2degrees service(s) and product(s) you purchase and use, including our [Fair Use Policy](http://www.2degreesmobile.co.nz/fairusepolicy);
  * Offering you rewards, special offers, competitions and other promotions; 
  * Providing you with information on new 2degrees product(s) and service(s) and/or products and services of carefully selected third parties we think you might like. When we get in touch via email or SMS, you agree that these marketing messages from us and our third party friends don't need to include an option to unsubscribe in the message;
  * Responding and following up on any queries, complaints or requests you might have made, and other customer care issues;
  * Complying with legal, governmental or regulatory agencies’ requests in connection with the regulation of telecommunications services, and in connection with any legal proceedings, crime or fraud prevention or detection, or prosecution;
  * Training our staff, monitoring our network(s) and service(s), and maintaining our system(s).
  * [Providing handset location information](https://www.2degreesmobile.co.nz/termsofuse/mobile-caller-emergency-location-service/) to emergency services including Fire, Police and Ambulance when you dial 111”

You agree that we and our agents may send you marketing messages, electronic or otherwise, about (amongst other things) our rewards, special offers, competitions and other promotions, and those of our agents or third parties which we consider may be of interest to you.  You may unsubscribe from receiving marketing messages from us and our agents at any time through Your 2degrees.

### Disclosure

Sometimes we may disclose your information to third parties (some of whom may be located outside of New Zealand). These third parties may include:

  * Dealers and suppliers whose products and services support our service(s) or our network(s), including the providers of infrastructure where your information is processed, and providers involved with monitoring and protecting the operation and security of our network(s);
  * Our dealers and agents, contractors and advisers;
  * Other network operators as required to provide and/or support the product(s) and service(s) we provide to you;
  * Credit reference agencies (if you have agreed) who may share your information with other organisations and who may keep a record of the searches we make against your name;
  * If someone else pays your bill, such as your employer, that person;
  * Our advertisers, customers, potential customers and associates with whom we may share aggregated information such as user statistics and other information that does not personally identify you;
  * Persons we are legally obliged to provide your information to,  including law enforcement agencies (such as the police, or the Serious Fraud Office), emergency services, government departments and regulatory authorities, as well as any person or organisation authorised to obtain your information in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 and/or the Telecommunication Information Privacy Code 2003;
  * Other service providers who use our network(s) to provide services to you;
  * Any of our potential or actual assignees or transferees, such as a potential purchaser of our business.

### Monitoring

To maintain and improve the service(s) we provide to you, we may monitor and record calls you make to us or we make you.

### Caller Identification

Unless you request our caller line identification restriction service (CLIR) your mobile phone number may be displayed to the person you have called.  Where you have requested CLIR, we will prevent your mobile phone number being shown to the recipient of your calls. Your mobile phone number may however still be displayed to us, the emergency services, or when you send a text message.

### Analytics

Like many websites, we use web analytics services, like Google Analytics for example. These services use “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help us analyse how you use our site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored on servers belonging to the companies providing the analytic services. These companies will use this information to evaluate your use of our website, and to compile reports for 2degrees on the site’s activity (for example, number of visitors to our site, how long they spend on the site when they visit and their geographical location).  They may also transfer this information to their agents or where required to do so by law. The companies providing the web analytic services will not associate your IP address with any other data they hold. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. By using our website, you consent to the processing of data about you as set out above.

### Access and Correction

You can access personal information that we hold about you by contacting us in writing. If the information held by us is inaccurate, incomplete or not up to date you may ask us to correct the information. 

If you consent to receiving emails or other communications from us, but later change your mind, just let us know and we will take you off our list. Get in touch via our ‘Contact Us’ web page.

### Change in Policy

We may need to amend the terms of this Policy if our practices change. If we do so, we will post the updated version on our website (at [www.2degreesmobile.co.nz/privacy](http://www.2degreesmobile.co.nz/privacy)).
